# Jonah Farrow | Curriculum Vitae IBM

10 Otham Close, Canterbury, CT2 7QX | 07505484737 | farrowjonah24@gmail.com

### Personal Statement

Having thrived through my IBM & Extreme Blue internship, I am on track for a 1:1 finish at the University of Kent. I want to return to IBM with my experience and growth mindset to demonstrate my proactive and collaborative competence. I am a clear communicator with a record of delivering business results to directors, distinguished engineers, and external clients - and I know how to strike a balance when dealing with different end users.

## Skills & Abilities

**Strong Agile Principles** - 12 months in a deeply integrated agile squad. Improved workflow of team and sizing meetings by limiting the number of developers attending to only key members, maintaining story sizing accuracy, and increasing workflow across the squad.

Innovation to overcome technical challenges - I contribute towards bi-weekly retrospectives. This ritual is a chance to improve as a team, and as individuals, to overcome weekly challenges. I create actionable tasks such as creating an online workshop to show my team how we can return to work safely and use new tools for hot desking.

**Breaking complexity down** - I aim to understand the priority of the work I am tasked with. I apply divide and conquer to create bite-size elements. Additionally, I maintain a high level of transparency in my work as I continually document my progress and any blockers along the way.

**Highly Engaging and Collaborative -** Translated technical knowledge early into consumable value for non-technical SREs to recreate the system we developed into a production environment.

New Technical Skills: Kubernetes, IBM Z, Bash, Rust, Linux, Terraform, IBM Cloud Experienced Technical Skills: Java, SQL, PHP, Go, C#, Erlang, Haskell, Git

# Experience

Extreme Blue Intern - IBM

Jun 2022- Sep 2022

Redesigned the way customers shop by introducing digital ownership of products for large UK retailers.

Software Developer - IBM

Jun 2021 - Jun 2022

Trailblazed 'one-click' solution for updating cloud resources. Decreased downtime of cloud resources during an update from a day to a few hours. Delivered a new update process into an easily consumed one-button solution.

**Provided Clarity to End-Users through Implementing Runbooks.** Provided solutions for a client-impacting issue by creating a series of high-quality runbooks. Quality was ensured by relentlessly collaborating with my team and clients to iteratively improve the outcome of my work.

#### IT Technician - The Skills Network

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

Demonstrated coordination and accuracy in transforming workspace within a team. Sustained consistent workflow utilising ticketing system. Minimised future upgrade costs by implementing end-users needs carefully, resolved software problems, and upgraded computers for end-users to mitigate the impact on their workflow.

## Education

University of Kent - BSc Computer Science, Canterbury 1st: 92% 2nd: 78%

2019 - Present

Cloud, Algorithms, OOP, Databases 80%

Created minesweeper game, a word analyser, a haunted house game using test driven development, and Jack language interpreter using Java.

Selby College - Extended Diploma in IT (Level 3) 100% - Triple Distinction Star

2017 - 2019

## Communication

- Communicated weekly technical demonstrations to my Director and Distinguished Engineers as part of a critical strategic initiative to demonstrate performance improvements for part of IBM Cloud.
- Weekly playbacks delivered to IBM'ers demonstrating progress with Extreme Blue internship, listened to feedback and put into action for future playbacks.
- Prepared internal playbacks when appropriate to my ex-team to demonstrate software that would improve progress along our roadmap.

# Leadership

I lead the Education Squad - I am responsible for delivering high-quality presentations to the intern community. I'm proactive in discussions and enable team members in meetings.

I lead my Extreme Blue Squad - With my IBM placement complete, I used my prior knowledge and the internship to grow my leadership skills in a team of other interns.